

$>\!\!<$

lssuseendharlal@gmail.com

+91-8012543335/+91-7904217073



Chennai, India



08 August, 1996



suseendhar.netlify.app

in

linkedin.com/in/suseendhar-lal-312709155

(7)

github.com/suseendharlal96

TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACTJS/REDUX, NEXTJS, GASTBYJS, MATERIAL UI, SEMANTIC UI, REACT BOOTSTRAP.

BACK END DEVELOPMENT

NODEJS, APOLLO GRAPHQL, MONGODB, REST API, FIREBASE, POSTMAN.

HOSTING PLATFORMS

NETLIFY, HEROKU, AWS.

VERSION CONTROL

GIT

IDE & CMS

VISUAL STUDIO CODE & CONTENTFUL CMS

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hind

Limited Working Proficiency

Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency

Sourashtra

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

SUSEENDHAR LAL LS

Software Engineer

Having 2 and half years of experience in IT Infrastructure as a Full stack developer on developing and hosting Web Applications, I take responsibility of developing responsive sites using HTML, CSS and JS along with latest frameworks and libraries like Reactjs, Redux, Nodejs, Mongodb. As a good team player, I've developed websites using Reactjs, Redux, Nodejs, Mongodb along with GraphQL from the scratch which includes all the authentication and core stuffs for a website.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software EngineerObject Frontier Software

02/2019 - Present

Project Mangement System & Work Order Management System

My responsibility:

- Developed a tool which manages all the project an organization has acquired and tracks all the statistics of the project along with client details and billing information which is currently used by 70 plus managers and CEO of my current organization.
- React along with Redux is used as Front end stack for developing the application.
- Responsiveness is achieved using React-Bootstrap, SCSS.
- Created RESTful services using NodeJs and stored data on Mongodb using mongoose as ORM.
- Used React hook form for client-side validations and React router for navigations.
- Implemented JWT tokens and encryption for authentication on server side and participated in knowledge building activities and incorporated it in everyday tasks.

Software Engineer trainee

Object Frontier Software

09/2018 - 02/2019

Achievements/Tasks

□ Trained in JavaScript, Object-oriented programming and frameworks like Angular and React.

Built a full stack application using React as front-end, Node for RESTful API's and MongoDB using Mongoose ORM.

EDUCATION

BE Computer Science

Rajalakshmi Engineering College

08/2014 - 04/2018

Chennai

Chennai

Chennai

CERTIFICATES

- Problem Solving(Data Structures) Javascript Cascading Style Sheet Issued by HACKERRANK
- ReactJs Vuejs HTML/CSS Issued by UDEMY
- Machine Learning Issued by Coursera

PERSONAL WORKS

- Projects
- LeetCode Profile

INTERESTS

Listening to music

Watching movies

Working on Mini projects

Solving leetcode(31) and Hackkerank problems